Side Flexion Sitting On The Ball With The Weights By The Side is an option if you can do this exercise standing up.
I'm going to warn you that you must have small weights because if the weights are too big, they're really going to interfere, the size is going to interfere with the ball.
So it's not a good idea if you're ready to use heavier weights.
This is for lighter weights or no weights if you're starting to train your core and you need to start just learning how to do the exercise.
Now sitting on the fitness ball, it's going to take you to where you're sitting on your sit bones and you're spine is going to be align, shoulders down and back.
So you're chest is open and up.
So none of this, okay.
Now, the weights by the side, you're going to keep your head align as you take an inhale, and take a side, it's like a side crunch.
Exhale as you're coming up, inhale, exhale, inhale, exhale.
Now way to make it a little more challenging on the balance is maybe lifting your heels off the floor.
So you're kind of have a smaller base for your support of, on the ball that you're sitting.
And again, you want to make sure that you keep the weights small, or maybe you have wrist weights, wrist bands that you can wear instead because weights are going to be a problem with the size and the ball being right there where the path of the weights need to be.
So again, also, keep in mind that the head wants to go with the rest of the spine, none of that or none of that.
So you want to make sure that maybe you check in the mirror or in the reflection or somebody, spot you for a bit until your muscle memory develops, do a feel on each side and you're on a way to a happy, healthy core.
See you soon.